A Finding Aid to the Betty Parsons Gallery records and personal papers, circa 1920-1991, bulk 1946-1983, in the Archives of American Art AAA.parsbett
Archives of American Art
- Betty Parsons Personal Papers, circa 1927-1991; Series 7; (Boxes 38-51; 11.5 linear feet)
  7.4: Pocket Diaries and Notebooks, 1933-1981
  7.5: Annotated Sketchbooks, 1951-1969
  7.6: Writings by Others, circa 1950-1980
  7.7: Printed Material, circa 1927-1991
  7.8: Betty Parsons Art Work Files, circa 1955-1983
  7.9: Betty Parsons Private Collection Files, circa 1963-1983
  7.10: Personal Financial Records, 1947-1980
  - Early Curatorial Files, circa 1940-1958; 7.1
    This subseries consists of files that Parsons retained from her work at the Wakefield Gallery and the Mortimer Brandt Gallery. Files include correspondence, clippings, group exhibition files, announcements, catalogs, photographs, and exhibition and price lists.
    Early Curatorial Files are arranged into two sub subseries:
    7.1.1: Wakefield Gallery, circa 1940-1944
    7.1.2: Mortimer Brandt Gallery, circa 1944-1958
    - Wakefield Gallery, circa 1939-1944; 7.1.1
      Found here are files from Betty Parsons' job as director of the Wakefield Gallery, including clippings, correspondence, announcements, exhibition files, exhibition lists, schedules, invoices, receipts and a scrapbook of clippings and exhibition announcements created from a bound dummy copy of A Treasury of Art Masterpieces. There are no solo exhibition files, only files for the themed exhibitions, Love in Art (1941), Ballet in Art (1942), and Pre-Columbian Stone Sculpture (1944). The Pre-Columbian Stone Sculpture exhibition files are of particular note as they contain vintage photographs by Aaron Siskind of the sculptures that were produced for reproduction in the exhibition catalogue.
      - Clippings, circa 1941-1944 (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, circa 1941-1944 (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Exhibition Annoucements, circa 1940-1944 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Love in Art (1941), circa 1940-1941 (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Ballet in Art (1942), circa 1942; (Partially scanned) (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - Pre-Columbian Stone Sculpture (1944), circa 1944; (3 folders) (Box 38, Folder 12-14)
      - Pre-Columbian Stone Sculpture (1944) - Photographs, Works of Art, circa 1944; (vintage prints by Aaron Siskind; not scanned) (Box 38, Folder 15)
      - Exhibition Schedules and Lists, circa 1941-1944 (Box 38, Folder 16)
      - Invoices and Receipts, 1940-1944 (Box 38, Folder 17)
      - Scrapbook, 1939-1941 (Box 38, Folder 18)
      - Transcript of Radio Program The Artist Reviews Art, 1943 (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - Mortimer Brandt Gallery, circa 1944-1958; 7.1.2
      Found here are select files stemming from Betty Parsons work as the head of the contemporary art section of Mortimer Brandt Gallery. The files consist of clippings, correspondence, announcements, catalogs, exhibition files, and exhibition lists. As with the files from Wakefield Gallery above, these files do not constitute a complete record of Parsons' work with the Mortimer-Brandt Gallery. Exhibition files exist solely for the two exhibitions; Abstract and Surrealist Art in America (1944) and Portraits of Today by Painters of Tomorrow (1945). There is also correspondence between Parsons and Mortimer Brandt, some of which concerns lease arrangements for Parsons subletting half of the fifth floor of 15 East 57th Street to open her own gallery. There is also correspondence between Parsons and Sidney Janis, who sublet the rest of the floor for his gallery beginning in 1953.
      - Clippings, circa 1945-1946 (Box 38, Folder 20)
      - Correspondence, circa 1944-1958 (Box 38, Folder 21)
      - Exhibitions Annoucements and Catalogs, circa 1944-1946 (Box 38, Folder 22)
      - Abstract and Surrealist Art in America (1944), circa 1944; (2 folders) (Box 38, Folder 23-24)
      - Portraits of Today by Painters of Today (1945), circa 1945 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Exhibition file, Portraits of Today by Painters of Today (1945)- Photographs, Works of Art, circa 1945; (2 folders; not scanned; see also Box 51) (Box 39, Folder 2-3)
      - Lists of Exhibitions and Lenders, circa 1944-1947 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Portraits of Today by Painters of Today (1945) - Photographs, Works of Art, circa 1945; (See also Box 39, F2; not scanned) (Box 51 (sol))
  - Biographical Material, circa 1932-1983; 7.2
    Found here are scattered personal papers, such as Parsons' artist biography, family trees for the Pierson and Miles families, association membership cards, interview transcripts, travel itineraries, photographs, and mailing list of invitees for Parsons' Memorial. The folder containing miscellaneous personal papers includes ephemera, handwritten notes, an American Red Cross employment application, a small watercolor landscape by Lynn Yarnell, and several unsigned sketches.
    Photographs in this subseries include snapshots and professional portraits, the bulk of which span the mid-1960s to early 1980s. Most of the photographs feature Parsons, but there are photographs of others that are not identified as well as beach views, perhaps taken near her Southold, Long Island Studio. Additionally there is a folder of photographs of works of art, primarily paintings, depicting Betty Parsons.
    The bulk of the files in this series chronicle Betty Parsons' activities related to the art world. As a renowned art dealer and respected artist, Parsons' was a frequently requested speaker, juror for juried art exhibitions, and awards honoree. Her participation at these events is recorded through correspondence, invitations, programs, and award certificates. Noteworthy files include "The Creative in Art" seminar at Sarah Lawrence College, which includes syllabus and extensive notes for ten lectures. There is also a group of folders that document her social and volunteer activities.
    This subseries has been scanned in its entirety, except for photographs of artwork.
    - Artist Biography and Narratives, 1949-1982 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Family Trees and Histories, 1948 and undated (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Interview - WNYC (Radio Station) Art Festival, 1951, October 16 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Interview with Colette Roberts, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Invitations, Announcements and Programs, circa 1928-1979 (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Juries, Seminars, Lectures, and Awards (Box 39)
      - Althena Award,Rhode Island School of Design, 1981-1982; (2 folders) (Box 39, Folder 10-11)
      - Awards and Honors, circa 1960-1982 (Box 39, Folder 12)
      - Conference of Women in the Visual Arts, 1972 (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - Creative Arts Award, Brandeis University, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 14)
      - Honorary Degree, Mount Holyoke College, 1981 (Box 39, Folder 15)
      - Seminar at Sarah Lawrence College, 1971-1972; (2 folders) (Box 39, Folder 16-17)
      - Watercolor Society of Alabama, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 18)
      - Zaner Gallery, 1981 (Box 39, Folder 19)
      - General, circa 1950-1974 (Box 39, Folder 20)
      - General Juries, Seminars, etc., 1975-1976; (3 folders) (Box 39, Folder 21-23)
      - General Juries, Seminars, etc., 1976-1977 (Box 39, Folder 24)
      - General Juries, Seminars, etc., 1977-1978 (Box 39, Folder 25)
      - General Juries, Seminars, etc., 1979-1980 (Box 39, Folder 26)
      - General Juries, Seminars, etc., 1980-1981; (2 folders) (Box 39, Folder 27-28)
    - Membership Cards and Certificates, circa 1940-1980 (Box 39, Folder 29)
    - Memorial Service, 1982 (Box 39, Folder 30)
    - Personal Papers, miscellaneous, circa 1934-1990 (Box 39, Folder 31)
    - Photograph, Black and White Transparency, circa 1960-1970; (Not scanned) (Box 39, Folder 32)
    - Photographs, General, circa 1935-1981; (3 folders) (Box 39, Folder 33-35)
    - Photographs of Art Works depicting Betty Parsons, circa 1934-1940; (Not scanned) (Box 39, Folder 36)
    - Travel Itineraries and Documentation, 1949-1972 (Box 39, Folder 37-38)
    - Volunteer and Social Activities (Box 39)
      - Cosmopolitan Club, 1959-1980 (Box 39, Folder 39)
      - Louis Comfort Tiffany Foundation, 1980-1981 (Box 39, Folder 40)
      - Paul Taylor Dance Company, 1974-1980; (2 folders) (Box 39, Folder 41-42)
      - Visiting Nurse Service, 1971-1972 (Box 39, Folder 43)
      - Miscellaneous, 1949-1975 (Box 39, Folder 44)
    - War Ration Coupons, 1942-1943 (Box 39, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence, circa 1932-1983; 7.3
    Series consists of Parsons' incoming and outgoing correspondence originally maintained within her personal papers, although it appears to be a mixture of personal and professional correspondence. It includes not only letters from friends and family, but also from museum directors, art dealers, researchers, gallery artists, and artists seeking representation from the Betty Parsons Gallery.
    Correspondence is arranged into two sub-subseries:
    7.3.1: General Correspondence, circa 1932-1982
    7.3.2: Chronological Correspondence, circa 1938-1983
    General correspondence primarily consists of personal letters from friends, while chronological correspondence includes primarily business-related letters. No attempt was made to reconcile the two systems since this arrangement may have originated with the creator. This subseries has been scanned in its entirety.
    - General Correspondence, circa 1932-1982; 7.3.1
      Files mostly consist of correspondence with friends and artists with whom Parsons had a personal relationship, although letters touching upon gallery business are scattered throughout. As close friends, many of the artists shared details about their personal and family life, travels, work, and careers. Gallery artist correspondents include Larry Bigelow, Alexander Calder, and William Condon. Of particular note are letters from Ad Reinhardt discussing his work in relation to the gallery and exhorting Parsons to fight for her (and his) rightful place in history. Another significant and prolific correspondent is the English artist Adge Baker, with whom Parsons had a romantic relationship. The two lived together for several years in the house that Parson purchased shortly after she arrived in Paris in 1923. Although they separated in 1932, they remained life long friends.
      Notable friends and other correspondents include heiress and world-class speed boat racer Joe Carstairs, the Marchioness of Dufferin and Ava (Lindy Guinness), art critic Rosalind Constable, and art and literary critic Dale McConathy, who briefly worked for Parsons as a gallery assistant. Personal correspondence also includes Christmas cards, postcards, telegrams, and third party correspondence to gallery employees and Lee Hall, Parsons' biographer and gallery artist. Letter files are arranged alphabetically, postcards are arranged by decade, but Christmas cards are not in any order since it was difficult to determine dates or the full names of the correspondents.
      - A, circa 1951-1977 (Box 39, Folder 46)
        Alper, Natalie
        Andre, Carl
        Arlasez, Nuri
        Avery, Milton
        Auerbach, Ellen
      - Alloway, Lawrence, circa 1959-1975 (Box 39, Folder 47)
      - B, 1944-1982 (Box 39, Folder 48)
        Barcley, Jo
        Barker, Margaret
        Bakwa, C?©lestin,
        Beal, John
        Bedell, Eleanor
        Bess, Forrest
        Biero, Ellen
        Blume, Mary
        Bochoo, Jac[kki]
        Bove, Louise
        Box, Eden (Eden Fleming)
        Braddock, Barrie
        Bradley, Harvey
        Breckenridge, Edith (Mrs. Gerald)
        Brett, D.E.
        Brotherton, Joe
        Buchanan, Beverly
        Budd, [David]
        Burnhome, Clement M.
      - Baker, Adge, circa 1932-1982; (2 folders) (Box 39, Folder 49-50)
      - Baker, Adge, circa 1932-1982; (17 folders) (Box 40, Folder 1-17)
      - Barker, Walter, 1963-1979 (Box 40, Folder 18)
      - Bigelow, Larry, 1954-1960 (Box 40, Folder 19)
      - Bonge, Dusti, circa 1954-1982 (Box 40, Folder 20)
      - Bulla, Jean, circa 1932-1935 (Box 40, Folder 21)
      - C, 1948-1972 (Box 40, Folder 22)
        C., Bill
        Calder, Alexander
        Chryssa
        Coggeshall, Calvert
        Copley, Al
        Cummings, Harry
      - Carstairs, Joe, 1942-1963 (Box 40, Folder 23)
      - Clarke, Billie, circa 1970-1980 (Box 40, Folder 24)
      - Cloos, Consuelo, circa 1952-1982 (Box 40, Folder 25)
      - Congdon, William, 1977-1981 (Box 40, Folder 26)
      - Constable, Rosalind, 1943-1982 (Box 40, Folder 27)
      - Crosby, Caresse, 1925, 1965-1967 (Box 40, Folder 28)
      - D, 1952-1982 (Box 40, Folder 29)
        Daniels, Alfred
        Davidson, Carol Kreeger
        Davis, Mary
        Day, Blanche
        De Lamar, Alice
        Denn, Gene
        Dickinson, Dennis
        Dienes, Sari
        Dlugoszewski, Lucia
        Donaldson, James R.
        Donati, Enrico
        Dora, Una
        Dunbar, J. H.
      - DeMeyer, Evelyn, 1977-1980 (Box 40, Folder 30)
      - Dufferin and Ava, The Marchioness of (Lindy Guinness), circa 1964-1981 (Box 40, Folder 31)
      - Durant, Nancy, circa 1950-1972 (Box 40, Folder 32)
      - E, circa 1950-1982 (Box 40, Folder 33)
        Eastman, Thomas
        Eberhart, Betty
        Edelstein, Paul
        Egan, Charles
        Englesmith, Tejas
      - F, circa 1940-1982 (Box 40, Folder 34)
        Fairweather, Sally
        Falkenstein, Claire
        Feeley, Paul and Helen
        Fenno, Pauline
        Fine, Albert
        Fini, Jan Luigi
        Fischel, Marguerite
        Fish, Seena
        Fitch, Susan
        Flaherty, Frances Moore
        Flaherty, Frances Rohr
        Francisco, Marjorie
        Francisco, Richard
        Frankel, Anita
        Fraser, C. E.
        Freedberg, Priscilla
        Fremantle, Chloe
        Frickner, Lawrence
      - Frasetto, Monica Flaherty, circa 1951-1974 (Box 40, Folder 35)
      - Fritzius, Harry, circa 1953-1978 (Box 40, Folder 36)
      - G, 1948-1982 (Box 40, Folder 37)
        Garston, Gerald D.
        Gladstone, Doria and Mike
        George, Thomas
        Goff, Lloyd
        Gordon, Martha
        Grant-Govar, Enid
        Gray, Cleve
        Greenfield, Sophia
        Groth, Jan
        Guiness, Alec
      - Gooding, Maria, 1977-1982 (Box 40, Folder 38)
      - Groves, Chris, 1966-1968 (Box 40, Folder 39)
      - H, circa 1940-1981 (Box 40, Folder 40)
        Hamblett, Theora
        Hamilton, C.
        Hamilton, George Heard
        Harman, E. Terry
        Harper, Lindsay
        Harwood, Nina Conan Doyle
        Hawkins, Erick
        Hayashi, Kaname
        Herbert, David
        Hero, Mrs. Alvin (Martha)
        Herzel, Eileen
        Hillis, Sue
        Hock, Robert
        Hood, Dorothy Gregory
        Hooker, R. Wolcott
        Hopkins, Harry L.
        Humphrey, Ralph
        Huyck, Laura Talmage
      - Hall, Lee, circa 1981-1982 (Box 40, Folder 41)
      - Hennessy, Timothy, 1961-1974 (Box 40, Folder 42)
      - I and J, 1942-1982 (Box 40, Folder 43)
        Irving, Flora W.
        Jablow, Evelyn
        Jackson, Kay
        Jaeger, Blanche
        Jenkins, R.A.
        Johnson, Ray
      - K, circa 1940-1982 (Box 40, Folder 44)
        Kardamatis, Yiannis Wolfgang
        Katz, Bill
        Kealy, Hinman L.P.
        Kelleher, M. Landreth
        Kelly, Ellsworth
        Kent, Alice
        Klyne, Maurice
        Koch, Ed
        Koteen, Shirley
      - L, circa 1942-1981 (Box 40, Folder 45)
        Leake, Paul M.
      - M and N, circa 1950-1976 (Box 40, Folder 46)
        Macy, Gert
        Mallory, Margaret
        Marshall, George
        Mason, Susanne
        McCloud, Lillard
        McPeck, Eleanor
        Metz, Gwyn
        Miles, Jeanne
        Miller, B.
        Mon, Bascha
        Morgan, Joseph P.
        Mueller, Leo
        Muelanzambi, Bawka
        Murphy, Alice Harold
        Negulesco, Jean
        Nuala (Elsa de Brun)
      - McConathy, Dale, circa 1963-1969 (Box 40, Folder 47)
      - Newcomb, Mary (Mrs. Alexander Higginson), circa 1932-1961 (Box 40, Folder 48)
      - O and P, circa 1950-1982 (Box 40, Folder 49)
        Oliver, Alex
        Okada, Kenzo and Kimi
        Passante, Anne
        Perreault, John
        Perkins, Helvetia
        Porter, Aline
        Porter, Pat
        Pousette-Dart, Richard
        Putnam, Wallace
      - Pierson, James Rhodes, 1956-1959 (Box 40, Folder 50)
      - R and S, 1943-1981 (Box 40, Folder 51)
        Russell, Ethel Bordon
        Santiago, Ed
        Shepley, Mrs. P. R. (Lili)
        Sikelianos, Eva
        Smith, Tony
        Sottsass, Ettore
        Steindecker, Oliver
        Steiner, Lisl
        Sterne, Hedda
        Stevens, Peter Jellen
        Storey, Ala
        Swartz, Clementa M.
      - Reinhardt, Ad, circa 1949-1965 (Box 40, Folder 52)
      - Seid, Dui, circa 1974-1975 (Box 40, Folder 53)
      - T, circa 1961-1975 (Box 40, Folder 54)
        Taylor, Benjamin de Brie
        Taylor, Marie Carr
        Thompson, Lynne
        Toland, Mrs. Owen Jones
        Tryggvadottir, Nina
        Tumarkin, Igael
      - V, W, and Z, circa 1956-1982 (Box 41, Folder 1)
        Valente, Barbara
        Valmarsus, Pablo and Rene
        Vanruska, Frank
        Van Scriver, Strelsa
        W., Jack
        West, Saul and Peggy
        Zito, Abby
      - Unidentified, circa 1932-1981 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Third Party, circa 1937-1983 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Christmas Cards, circa 1960-1977; (5 folders) (Box 41, Folder 4-8)
      - Postcards, circa 1930-1959 (Box 41, Folder 9)
      - Postcards, circa 1960-1969 (Box 41, Folder 10)
      - Postcards, circa 1970-1979 (Box 41, Folder 11)
      - Postcards, 1980-1982 (Box 41, Folder 12)
      - Postcards, undated (Box 41, Folder 13)
      - Telegrams, 1929-1971 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Chronological Correspondence, circa 1938-1983; 7.3.2
      These files reflect how deeply Parsons' life was intertwined with the gallery as correspondence with dealers, museum directors, researchers, collectors, arts organizations, gallery staff, and artists predominate in this subseries, although letters from friends are scattered throughout. Letters address a variety of topics including requests for Parsons to be a jurist for juried exhibitions, exhibitions and sales of her own art work, references for artists, requests for interviews, questions from researchers, and communications from gallery staff. Letters from Jock Truman, include his original cover letter (1961) and updates concerning gallery business (1964, 1966-1968, and 1972).
      Letters from Parsons include a letter of introduction for her former husband Schuyler Parsons to Peggy Guggenheim (1965) and a suggestion to collector Paul Mellon (1976)that Barnett Newman's Stations of the Cross belongs in the National Gallery of Art, Washington, D.C.. Parsons response to a researcher (1979) provides her insights concerning the early history of the gallery and her connection with the Abstract Expressionists. Other significant correspondents include Ossip Zadkine (1956), Jacqueline Monnier (1978 and 1982), and Judith Rothschild (1980). Finally, letters that post-date Parsons death in July, 1982 include condolence letters to gallery staff and correspondence between Jack Tilton, her former assistant at the gallery and William Rayner, her nephew and the executer of her estate, to establish prices for her art work.
      Files are arranged chronologically by year, followed by a file of undated letters
      - Correspondence, 1938-1949 (Box 41, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence, 1950-1953 (Box 41, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence, 1954-1956 (Box 41, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence, 1957-1960 (Box 41, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 41, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 41, Folder 20)
      - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 41, Folder 21)
      - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 41, Folder 22)
      - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 41, Folder 23)
      - Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 41, Folder 24)
      - Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 41, Folder 25)
      - Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 41, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 27)
      - Correspondence, 1979; (2 folders) (Box 41, Folder 28-29)
      - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 30)
      - Correspondence, 1981; (2 folders) (Box 41, Folder 31-32)
      - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 41, Folder 33)
      - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 41, Folder 34)
      - Correspondence, undated (Box 41, Folder 35)
  - Pocket Diaries and Notebooks, circa 1933-1982; 7.4
    Files primarily consist of small Smythson leather pocket diaries in which Parsons noted lunch and dinner engagements, openings, and other appointments, thereby providing a sense of her daily activities. As with Parsons' life, personal and gallery life are intertwined in the pages. Frequently the endpapers were used to note names, address and phone numbers. Although these diaries span from 1933-1980, they are not complete; there are only a few from the 1940s and none from the 1950s. Address books and desk calendars are also found.
    Three notebooks from the 1960s appear to relate to gallery business as they contain references, to artists, works of art, and museums. The 1980-1982 notebook contains handwritten drafts of correspondence; most of the notebook pages are left blank.
    - Address Books, circa 1933-1978 (Box 41, Folder 36)
    - Pocket Diaries, 1933-1936 (Box 41, Folder 37)
    - Pocket Diary, 1937 (Box 41, Folder 38)
    - Pocket Diaries, 1937-1938 (Box 41, Folder 39)
    - Pocket Diaries, 1939-1941 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Pocket Diaries, 1942-1943 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Pocket Diaries, 1948-1949 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Pocket Diaries, 1960-1961 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Pocket Diaries, 1962 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Pocket Diaries, 1963-1964 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Pocket Diaries, 1965-1966 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Pocket Diaries, 1967-1969 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Pocket Diaries, 1970-1971 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Pocket Diaries, 1972-1973 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Pocket Diaries, 1974-1975 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Pocket Diaries, 1976-1977 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Pocket Diaries, 1978-1980 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Pocket Diaries, 1981 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Engagement Calendar, 1970 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Engagement Calendar, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - Engagement Calendar, 1980 (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - Notebook, 1961 (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - Notebook, possibly 1965 (Box 42, Folder 19)
    - Notebook, 1980-1982 (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Annotated Sketchbooks, 1951-1969; 7.5
    This subseries includes three sketchbooks, two of which are annotated. According to biographical accounts, Betty Parsons was an avid sketcher, having acquired the habit dating from her studies with the English artist Arthur Lindsay in the 1930s. Despite this fact, this collection contains only three sketchbooks. The 1951 sketchbook consists primarily of ink figure drawings, but also includes notes for her WNYC Radio Arts Festival Interview, a transcript of which can be found with the biographical materials. The 1967 sketchbook includes diary entries amongst the abstract and figurative drawings. Finally, the 1969 sketchbook is labeled "Turkey" and includes felt tip marker landscape and abstract drawings.
    - Sketchbook, 1951 (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - Sketchbook, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - Sketchbook, 1969 (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - Writings by Others, circa 1950-1980; 7.6